A Guide to the J. Daniel Pezzoni Collection, 1941-1999
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
J. Daniel Pezzoni Collection, 1941-1999
Library of Virginia
36181, 36502, 37120
0.675 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of J. Daniel Pezzoni, Lexington, Virginia, 2 December 1998, 20 August 1998, and 3 June 1999.
Biographical/Historical Information
J. Daniel Pezzoni is an architectural historian and historic preservation consultant.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of materials relating to Fort A.P. Hill, Blacksburg, South Hill, Virginia art and artists such as Betty Branch and Tedd Blevins, Bassett Furniture Company, First Baptist Church in Salem, Route 58 in Grayson County, outdoor activities, theater, and Roanoke Democratic Party politics. The Fort A. P. Hill materials include archeological and architectural surveys, an installation diary from 1941-1945, a history of the army base, and photographs of buildings.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: I. Fort A.P. Hill; II. Miscellaneous.
Contents List
- Fort A. P. Hill (Box 1)
  - An Archeological Survey of a Proposed Ammunition Storage Point, Fort A. P. Hill, Virginia (1991) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A History of Fort A. P. Hill by Gerald T. Evans (1993) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Installation Diary, Headquarters, Camp A. P. Hill, Virginia (photocopy), 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Phase I Cultural Resources Inventory of Fort A. P. Hill, Carolina County, Virginia (I-IV) (Box 1, Folder 4-7)
  - Phase I Cultural Resources Survey, Caroline County Regional Jail Site, Fort A. P. Hill, Caroline County, Virginia (May 1993) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photographs (17) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous (Box 1-2)
  - Blacksburg, Virginia (I-II) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - A History of Bassett Furniture Industries, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - History of First Baptist Church, Salem, Virginia, 1867-1997, by Carolyn H. Glover (March 1997) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - South Hill, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Phase I Cultural Resources Investigations of a 4.5 Mile Segment of Route 58 in Grayson County, Virginia (Apr. 1995) (I-IV) (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
  - Virginia Artists and Art (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, Brochures, and Newsletters (Box 2, Folder 6)